www.ispeaken.com
史上最值得看的50部英语动画片（双字幕）
布谷，这才叫河东狮吼
Now, that's a roar, Boog.
快上车吧，我们要迟到了
Now get in. We're gonna be late.
我认输了，那女的超会吼的 不过她会这一招吗？
No denying. The girl's got growl. But can she get down like this?
她会无影脚吗？ 看我，我才是世上最厉害的
Can you get down like this? Bring it here. Bring it.
看我的，看我的…
Then bring it right back, huh? Look at that. Look at that.
（请勿喂熊！）
呀呼！好戏上场！
Here it comes.
（山林村）
（枪枝与礼品）
早，戈帝
Hey, Gordy.
早，贝丝
Morning, Beth.
（打猎季节还有三天）
欢迎大家观赏 山林村的野生动物巨星秀
Welcome to Timberline's Wilderness Extravaganza.
我是管理员贝丝
I'm Ranger Beth.
现在请热烈掌声欢迎布谷
Please, put your hands together for Boog.
最威猛的大熊出场
Behold, the mighty grizzly.
说我恋爱，说我疯了
You can say I'm in love You could say I'm insane
只有我的爱枪箩琳最了解我
But no one understands me Like my darling Lorraine
你早熟晚熟 早晚都会被烤熟
Looks like you're going from one grill to another.
我们人气超旺的，对吧，布谷
We rocked that house, didn't we, Boog?
观众为我们疯狂了 为我疯，为你狂
They were eating out of our hands. Well, my hands, your paws.
“为我疯，为你狂”
Eating out of your paw.
不赖嘛，这个名字
That's good. That's going in the show.
看到那个烂人 我就觉得一肚子火
Shaw. That guy really chaps my khakis.
布谷，在这等我
You wait here, Boog.
逮捕他，戈帝 熊奶妈军团出场
- Cuff him, Gordy. - Oh, the Girl Scouts are here.
他又去盗猎了
He's at it again.
煞星，还有三天打猎季节才开始
Shaw, hunting season doesn't start for three days.
你的引擎盖上怎么会有一头鹿
What are you doing with that buck on your hood?
干嘛，关我屁事 是他自己傻不隆咚跑来撞我的卡车
What? It ain't my fault. He ran right in front of my truck.
哪里？高速公路？
Where, on the interstate?
就算是吧
Sort of.
漂亮美眉跑哪去了？
Where is that girl?
有够臭的
That's nasty.
哇靠，哇咧，怎么回事 这是哪里？
What? What the--? What's going on? Where am I?
我看见一道强光，两道强光
I saw a bright light and-- I saw two bright lights and...
-我挂了吗？ -快了
- Am I dead? - Not yet.
煞星的车撞得歪七扭八的
But seeing how that is Shaw's truck--
-煞星是啥？ -山林村里最烂的猎人
- What's a Shaw? - Only the nastiest hunter in town.
猎人，你也被抓了吗？
A hunter? Did he get you too?
你有看到我被五花大绑吗？
You don't see me tied up, do you, baby?
-这是我的酷车 -你的酷车？
- This is my ride. - Your ride?
对，这全是我的
Yeah, this is my town, okay?
村民跟我超麻吉的 这里是我的地盘
These are my people. This is where I reside.
没有人能猎捕我这头熊
Nobody's hunting this bear.
真的？那就把我解开 求求你，又没有人在看
Really? Well, then untie me. Please? Look, no one's looking.
-我办不到 -那我怎么办？
- Ain't gonna be able to do it. - What am I gonna do?
我不想变成墙上的鹿头
I don't wanna be mounted on a wall.
-安啦，不会的啦 -不会？
- Calm down. Ain't gonna happen. - It's not?
-你还不够格啦 -什么叫做我不够…？
- Not with that rack. - I don't have a problem with--
我的… 那是…
My... It's...
我变成独角鹿 不要瞄我，不要瞄我
I'm a unihorn. Don't look at me. Don't look at me.
我丑毙了，我是四不像
I'm hideous. I'm a monster.
- Tree-hugger. - Knuckle dragger.
-乡下土包子 -山顶洞人
笨熊奶妈
Veggieburger.
好了…你们不要吵了
All right, all right. That's enough, you two.
听好，笨熊奶妈 畜牲蠢到不行
Listen, Girl Scout, they're dumb animals.
我只是尊重大自然的法则 人最优，畜牲是最低等的
I'm just respecting the natural order: man on top, animals on the bottom.
你的熊… 不对…你的笨熊与众不同
But your bear-- Now, now, your bear is special.
他算是夹在中间的物种
He belongs somewhere in the middle.
是夹在两片面包里的烤熊沙威犸
Between two slices of rye, smothered in gravy.
煞星，你真的是超级变态的怪叔叔
You're a sick, sick, twisted puppy, Shaw.
帮我订两包QQ熊软糖好吗？
Put me down for a box of Thin Mints, will you, sweetie?
食古不化只会玩枪的臭老猴 布谷，我们走了
Six-toed gun monkey. Boog, come on, let's get out of here.
拜托，我求求你放了我吧
Come on, I'm begging you. Please, please. Just untie me.
我求求你…
Come on. Please, please, please?
快走啊，快窜回你的森林吧，兄弟
Hey, go on now. Scamper on back to the woods, little buddy.
独角小怪鹿
Little one-horned freak.
兄弟，他叫我兄弟
Buddy? He called me "buddy."
我的鹿
My buck.
我的车，你这个小…
My truck. Why, you little--
煞星，村里不准开枪
Shaw, no shooting in town.
可是戈帝… 那只熊用爪子放掉了我的鹿
But, Gordy, that bear leaned over and untied my buck.
-你没看到吗？ -我只看到破碎的车灯，煞星
- Didn't you see that? - All I see is a busted headlight.
你在森林里待太久得妄想症了
Shaw, you've been living in the woods too long.
管它妄想症、狂牛症 抓到那只鹿才是真的
They can't tell me what I seen, because only I know what I seen.
幸运大轮转！
Wheel of Fortune!
有人要赢大钱，快啊
Big money got to come. Come on.
-好了，老弟，该睡了 -现在奖金已经累积到十万了
- Okay, buddy, time for bed. - Five hundred--
-这一题还是没有猜中 -布谷
- There's no R-- - Boog.
小布丁在等你哦！
Mr. Dinkleman's waiting.
晚安，大个儿
Good night, big guy.
我是不是忘了什么了？
Oh, did I forget something?
不行…不能再多吃了
No, no, no. No more treats for you.
不行，别闹了
No, stop it.
别装可爱了，不要挤眉弄眼的
Not the face. Oh, no, not the eyebrows too.
撒娇也没有用 好了啦，我是说真的
No, it's not gonna work this time. Stop it. I'm serious, Boog.
很可爱，但是不行… 好吧
It's cute, but no-- All right.
如果你今天跑进森林 会碰到个大惊喜
If you go out in the woods today You're sure of a big surprise
如果你今天跑进森林 你最好伪装自己
If you go out in the woods today You'd better go in disguise
因为森林里每一只熊
For every bear That ever there was
都会在这里聚在一起
Will gather there together because
因为今天是熊宝宝的野餐日
Today's the day
熊宝宝的野餐日
The teddy bears have their picnic
晚安，布谷
Good night, Boog.
谁啊？
Who's there?
我警告你哦，我有熊爪哦 我一抓狂就会抓人哦
I'm warning you. I got ten claws and I ain't afraid to use them.
-兄弟，是我，爱鹿特啦 -你跑来干什么？
- Hey, buddy. It's me, Elliot. - What are you doing here?
你救了我，我是来报恩的
You helped me, I'm returning the favor.
我要救你离开这里 快点，我们走人
I'm busting you out of here. Let's go. Let's do this.
管理员出来我们就没戏唱了
Come on. Let's book it before the warden makes her rounds.
不对，鸡米花 你完全弄错了
No, cornflake. You've got it all twisted.
-这个地方是我家 -不错哦
- This here is my home. - Sweet.
现在你可以夹着尾巴滚出去了
Now haul your little butt back out that window.
-这是啥米？ -不准碰
- What's this? - Get off of that.
粉柔软哦… 那是什么？
So soft. What is that?
你在里面干什么？
What are you doing in there?
这里够大，两个人住刚刚好
This place is big enough for two.
-什么？ -这个不好，这个赞
- What? - Wow, look at that.
你看，有自然美吗？
Does this look natural?
-还给我 -这小家伙是谁？
- Give me that. - Oh, who's this little guy?
-小布丁 -小布丁？
- Dinkleman. - Dinkleman?
小布丁是你的洋娃娃？
Is Dinkleman your doll?
我才不在乎那破娃娃咧
I don't care about that old thing.
我懂了，你就是宠物
Oh, I get it. You're like a pet.
-我才不是宠物呢 -才怪
- I ain't nobody's pet. - Right.
我想怎样就怎样 大爷我要走要留，随我高兴
I do what I want, when I want, and I come and go as I please.
好啊，那就走吧！
Well, then let's go.
出去？
Outside?
我为什么要出去 我在里面什么都有…
Why would I wanna go outside when I got all I need in...
那是什么
Whoa, what's that?
我叫它“哇塞” 吃了就…哇塞！
I call them Woo Hoos, like:
想不想吃？
You want one?
我知道哪里有很多 但你得出来…
I know where there's a bunch of them, but you gotta go...
外面
...outside.
里面，外面
Inside. Outside.
-里面，外面 -别闻了
- Inside. Outside. - Stop it.
-笨鼻子 -里面，外…
- Stupid nose. - Inside. Outsi--
哇塞！
老哥，你吃的哇塞 就是从那里面翻出来的
Okay, I got that Woo Hoo right out of one of those container doohickeys.
从垃圾桶捡出来的？
You got that out the garbage?
害我吃得满嘴满脸都是
I had that in my mouth and everything.
你闻个不停，闻得我很烦耶
Dude, you're freaking me out with that nose thing.
-哇！ -什么状况？
- Whoa. - What is it?
-我看到一卡车的“哇塞” -赞啦
- It's a whole Woo Hoo village. - Sweet.
锁住了 我们还是明天再来好了
It's locked. Maybe we should come back tomorrow.
嘿！
Hey.
爱鹿特，你看你干的…好事
Elliot, look what you... You did.
你会把我给…给害死
You gonna get us in some trouble.
哇塞吃到饱
The Woo Hoo bar.
就像美眉一样，白泡泡幼绵绵
She's my lady. Smooth and creamy.
你好坏，不可以，管他咧
So bad, I shouldn't. Yet I will.
这是什么？
What is that?
哦，交给我处理
Whoa, let me try.
布谷…
Boog. Boog?
-哈，呆鹿特 -是爱鹿特
- Hello, idiot. - It's "Elliot."
我不是ET
I come in peace.
我发财了
I'm foraging.
披萨大餐
Pepperoni!
-劈腿，转圈 -布谷…玩完了，快闪
- All right. Yeah, there it is. Let's go. - Boog, party's over, let's go.
-来啊，正点… -不准动
- All right, yeah, there it is. - Freeze.
来啊，最威猛大熊 晚安
Behold, the mighty grizzly. Good night.
如果你今天跑进森林 可以吃…吃大炸鸡
If you go out in the woods today There's gonna be some fries
长颈鹿饼干
Yeah, and the giraffes...
吃起来好像大象饼干哦！
...they taste almost exactly like the elephants.
这全搞乱了
That's messed up.
戈帝
Hey, Gordy.
糟了，快点倒车 不能让她看到我
Back up quick, before she sees me.
你死定了，大个儿
You're in big trouble, mister.
你知道你吃糖的后果会怎样
You know what sugar does to you, Boog.
上床去，快去
Straight to bed, now!
真的很抱歉，都怪我 保证下不为例
I'm so sorry. It's my fault. It won't happen again.
-要是他伤了人怎么办？ -戈帝，拜托
- What if he had hurt someone? - Gordy, please.
-我们谈的是布谷耶 -看什么看？
- We're talking about Boog here. - Hey, what are you looking at?
我叫你不要等我的
I told you not to wait up.
-我知道…我会带他回森林 -你应该让他回到大自然去
- I'll take him back to the woods. - It's time to put him where he belongs.
不行…他还没有做好准备 我是说…不是我的错
No, no, he's not ready to go back yet. I mean, it's not my fault.
我教过他求生技能
I tried to teach him the basics.
我带他去捕鱼 可是他不想把脚弄湿
I took him fishing, but he didn't wanna get wet.
戈帝，别这样不要…
Gordy, please--
布谷对不起你
Boog is sorry.
-贝丝，你不是他妈妈 -我本来就不是
- Beth, you're not his mother. - I'm not mothering him.
抱歉… 立刻给我上床去
Excuse me. Go to bed, Boog!
再一个夏天
One more summer.
我别无所求，再一个夏天
That's all I'm asking, one summer.
太好了，看吧，我也可以讲理 谢了
Great, see? I can be reasonable. Thanks.
你很清楚
You know something?
你拖得越久 他就越难适应大自然的生存环境
The longer you wait, the harder it's gonna be for him to adapt.
放心，他一定会… 至少我觉得他会
Oh, I'm sure he'll... At least I think he'll--
到时候你会越舍不得…放他走
And the harder it's gonna be for you to let him go.
晚安，贝丝
Good night, Beth.
我该拿你怎么办才好？
What am I gonna do with you?
这不是低咖啡因的 你明知道咖啡因会害惨我
This isn't decaf. You know what caffeine does to me, Bob.
我会碎碎念，念到你耳朵出油
I'd be talking up a storm, chatting your ear off...
嘴角冒泡了，还停不下来
...a mile a minute for the whole ride.
腊肠先生，走了 走啦，腊肠先生
Mr. Weenie, heel. Heel, Mr. Weenie.
烫…
Hot.
好苦 非常苦，但又非常香醇
It's terrible but wonderful at the same time.
就像杯底不可以养金鱼
It's like freedom in a cup.
爽啦，乎干啦
Out of hand.
听说布谷昨天晚上跑出来乱
You know, I heard Boog got loose last night...
把这里搞得乱七八糟的
...and he totally trashed the place.
-真的？ -我干嘛骗你
- Really? - That's what happened.
这里感觉好像不太对劲
There's something wrong going on here.
畜牲，还会像人类一样走路…
You? It walks like a man.
不要跑 你这个边走路边喝拿铁的怪鹿
Hold still, you two-legged latte drinker.
小心
Look out!
别又来了
Not again.
布谷会让你们 好想拍拍你们的熊掌
Boog will have you eating out of his paw.
懂吗，熊掌 因为他是熊吗？
Get it? "Paw," because he's a bear?
-总之啊… -烦死了
- So anyway... - Oh, man.
放轻松，布谷，你做得到
Okay, relax, Boog. You can do this.
我要躲起来…
- What the--? - I gotta hide. I gotta hide.
你在乱什么？ 快出去啦
What are you doing? Get out of here. Hey.
有人在追杀我
He's right behind me.
我就知道，那只笨熊教坏我的鹿
I knew it. That bear's corrupted my buck.
掩护我
Hide me.
-好了，他走了，快出去 -好主意
- All right, he's gone. Now get out. - Good idea.
-你去哪？ -欢迎，最威猛的大熊
- Where you going? - Behold, the mighty grizzly.
好可爱的小毛驴
How cute, a donkey.
-你给我惹了一堆麻烦 -我…谁叫你救了我
- You got me in enough trouble. - Hey, I-- You saved my life.
活该，你救了我就有责任保护我
That means that you're responsible for me.
什么？ 你不要再来闹我了
What? Stop messing up my life.
你需要走出户外 你应该要谢谢我
You needed to get out. You should thank me.
-谢谢？ -不客气，兄弟
- Thank you? - You're welcome, buddy.
不要再那样叫我了 给我滚
Stop calling me that. Now get out.
我要躲起来…
Need to hide. Need to hide.
布谷？
Boog?
门都没有，滚出来
Oh, no, you don't. You're leaving now.
-马上出来 -不要
- Out of the coat. Take it off. - No. No!
-脱掉外套 -人家不依
- Take off the coat. - No means no.
-他要吃掉驴子了 -他要把我们全吃了
- He's eating the donkey. - He's gonna eat us all.
你明知道他还在外面
You know he's still out there.
吃人，他才不会 布谷你在干什么？
Eat you? He's not gonna-- Boog, what are you doing?
我要你立刻把他放下来听到没有
Put that animal down this instant.
-不要乱动 -不要，我偏要动
- Hold still. - No, I'm staying.
我正在演出
But my show!
坐下，布谷 我要你马上停下来
Sit, Boog. You're getting a time-out.
听见没？ 我真的要生气了
Do you hear me? I'm totally getting angry.
煞星那家伙 他想宰了我
That guy wants to kill me.
各位，不要走
No, wait.
-指甲断了 -指甲…
- I chipped a hoof. - Chipped a--?
那是蹄子 我要把你宰了
You chipped a-- I'm gonna kill you.
他很温驯，真的 不要慌…
He's harmless. Really. Stay calm. Stay calm!
闪边去，滚
Out of my way. Move.
没戏唱了，你这个四脚怪ㄎㄚ
Show's over, you four-legged freaks of nature.
太帅了
Perfect.
煞星，把枪放下
Shaw. Drop that gun.
你毁了我的秀
You're ruining my show.
冷静，排成一列
Easy, now. Just line them up.
一箭双雕
Two heads, one bullet.
头昏昏，脑钝钝
Buttermilk biscuits.
煞星，你被逮捕了
Shaw, you're under arrest.
煞星
Shaw?
戈帝，我… 我不知道该怎么办
Gordy, I didn't know what else to do. I--
是时候了，贝丝
It's time, Beth.
打猎季节很危险耶
But what about hunting season?
Take him above the falls. He'll be safe there.
送他到瀑布上面去，那里很安全
放心好了
You're gonna be...
你不会有事的
You're gonna be fine.
我会很想你，大个儿
I'm gonna miss you, big guy.
好美哦
Pretty.
我的家呢？ 不见了
Where's home? It's gone.
被人偷走了
Someone stole it.
小声一点好不好
Hey, could you keep it down?
我还想要再睡一下啦
I'm trying to sleep here.
都是你
You.
-我怎么了？ -你看清楚了，爱鹿特
- No, I didn't do it. - Take a good look, Elliot.
你看到什么了？ 什么东西不见了？
What do you see, Elliot? Something's missing, Elliot.
是什么，爱鹿特 是什么？
What is it, Elliot? What is it?
等等，不要说，我…
Wait, don't tell me. I...
山林村不见了
Timberline is missing!
-我本来要猜这个的 -我的车库不见了
- I was just gonna say that. - My garage is missing.
早餐、午餐、晚餐都不见了
Breakfast, lunch, and dinner are missing.
演艺事业不见了 这一切都是你害的
My life is missing, and it's all your fault.
不然你想怎么样？
What are you gonna do?
你好搞笑哦
You're funny.
我想你也许会…那我的小命就… 然后…
I thought, "Maybe," but then I was like... and then--
这是不可能的 一定是贝丝误会了
This ain't happening. It's some kind of mistake.
好好想想 她很气，但我可以搞定她
Think, Boog. She's mad, but you can fix this.
我要赶快回去对着她装可爱
All right, I'll go back and I'll give her the face.
装可爱
The face.
我现在就回去 免得她忘了我的可爱
Gotta get back before she forgets the face.
没错，只要靠我这张装可爱的脸 一切搞定
That'll clear it all up right there. Yeah, yeah, yeah, the face.
布谷
Boog!
你不能像这样到处乱闯乱逛
You can't just go wandering around out here.
你根本就不知道你要去哪里
You don't know where you're going, Boog!
我要回家去
I'm going home.
等等，布谷，我…
Wait. Boog.
我知道山林村怎么走
I know where Timberline is.
-我可以带你回去 -谢了，不必麻烦了
- I can get you back. - Thank you, but no thank you.
安静
Quiet.
山林村一定在这附近
Timberline's gotta be around here somewhere.
不错，满快的嘛
Well, that was quick.
让我想想 屁屁向左，屁屁向右
Now, let's see. Righty-tighty, lefty-loosey.
布谷，是你吗？
Boog, is that you?
布谷
Boog.
现在我只要摸清楚这个地方
Okay, I gotta get the lay of the land.
我只要…
Somehow...
爬到最高处就可以了
...if I get up high enough, then...
太好了
All right.
我做得到的
I can do this.
没问题啦
No problem.
你是什么玩意？ 到处乱逛
Lost your way to Sunday school, pal?
这里是妙酷鼠的地盘 没有人敢惹妙酷鼠
This is McSquizzy's turf. Nobody messes with McSquizzy.
因为他就是我
Because that's me.
-什么？ -你要是敢碰这棵树的话
- What? - Touch a needle in this tree...
-我就K得你满头包 -是吗？
- ...and I'll give you such a doing! - Yeah?
就凭你一个？
You and what army?
算你狠
Oh, that army.
不要惹火小松鼠军团
Mess not with the furrytail clan.
好料的捍卫者 正义的圣战士
Defenders of the good, crusaders of the righteous...
松树的守护神
...guardians of the pine.
谁稀罕啊 我去找另一棵就好了
Keep your tree. I'll find another one.
快看，熊妈妈背着熊娃娃
Look! He's got a wee freakish twin growing out of his back.
这棵不错
Oh, this one will work.
-啊呀！ -这只是个小小的警告
Hey. That was a warning, all right?
你再乱来 我就踹得你眼冒金星，鼻孔开花
Try that again, and I'll be kicking your furry brown bahookie!
这是另外一棵树耶
- What? - Hey, this is a different tree.
这全是我的树
They're all my trees.
我建议你闪远一点 滚回你原来的地方去
I suggest you turn round and head right back from whence you came.
我也想那么做啊 只要跟我说山林村怎么走
That's what I'm trying to do. So just point me the way to town...
我马上走人
...and I'll be out of here.
我受够了，这是你们自找的
That's it. You're asking for a whooping.
预备…
Ready!
发射
Fire!
布谷，快看，空手倒立哦
Hey, Boog, look. No hands.
太阳把我的屁股晒得红通通的
I think I'm getting a sunburn, though.
你看嘛
Check it out.
好啦，要怎么走？
All right, where's town?
也许我的屁股应该叫做猴子屁股
Or what we would call this, a moon burn.
你少打屁 快点说
Look, just give me the directions.
我真的很想回去
I really need to get back.
好可怜哦
So sad.
-你到底说不说？ -好啦…我说
- Where's Timberline? - Okay. Okay. All right.
你在山林村过得很享受吧
You got it good in Timberline, right?
有咖啡、哇塞棒，还有保全
Coffee, Woo Hoo bars, safety.
-那又怎样 -不过你还少了一样
- Yeah, so? - And still, something is missing.
-有吗？ -有，我
- There is? - Yep. Me.
让我参一ㄎㄚ，布谷 我带你回去
And I want in, Boog. I'll take you to town...
回到村里后，我们两个结拜
...but when we get there, we're partners.
怎么样啊？ 哥儿们
Deal, partner?
什么？ 不…不可以
What? Oh, no, no, no.
那是不可能的事，不可能
That ain't never gonna happen. Never.
难道你都没有家人吗？
Don't you have a herd to get back to?
家人，他们… 我家人他们会谅解的
What--? My herd? They-- My herd will understand.
那些鹿是…是我的好哥儿们
These guys are my-- They're my buddies.
-他…他们会祝福我的 -别作梦了
- They-- They want the best for me. - Forget it.
好吧，那我劝你快闪
Oh, well. Better start moving, then.
因为打猎季节过几天就要开始了
Because open season starts in a few days.
也许那些猎人会为了送你回家
Maybe one of those hunters can give you a ride back...
就把你绑在引擎盖上
...on the hood of their truck.
猎人，可恶
Hunters. Dang.
-好啦… -那我们讲定？
- Okay, okay. - So we have a deal, then?
好，我要你亲口说
Okay, let me hear you say it.
-好哥儿们？ -你很恶耶
- Partners? - You're disgusting.
-你说什么？ -我…哥儿们
- What was that? - I...
-抱歉，听不见 -我说我可以做好…
- Sorry, can't hear you. - I said, I guess...
好…哥儿们
...we can be partners.
好…哥儿们？
Partners?
一言为定
Partners.
心动不如马上行动
Okey-dokey, this way! Move it or lose it!
我一直在想 应该来搞个秘密手势
You know, we should have a secret handshake...
想代号什么的 超酷的化名
...and like nicknames and stuff. Like, cool nicknames, though.
我就叫你布谷侠
I'll call you Boogster...
你可以叫我超人特攻鹿
...and then you can call me The Incredible Mister E.
很赞吧 我自己想出来的
Isn't that great? I came up with that myself.
神来的一笔 这一切都会很酷
I made that up. You know, this is gonna be awesome.
只有你和我
It's just you and me.
那个热裤妞是你什么人？
Hey, who's the lady in the shorts?
希望还来得及
I hope I'm not too late.
他们出来一整夜了
They've been out here all night.
熊…
A bear...
和鹿竟然联手出击
...and a deer, working together.
这个阴谋诡计有多可怕？
How far does this conspiracy go?
还有哪些畜牲加入？ 妈妈咪呀…
What other animals are involved? God bless America!
但愿那些畜牲还没有造反
I hope the bald eagle hasn't turned.
不会…
No, no, no.
应该没事
Maybe they're right.
至少… 至少狗是人类最忠实的朋友
Maybe... Maybe old Shaw is crazy.
不会
Yeah, maybe.
郊外好宁静哦，巴伯
Isn't it peaceful out here, Bob?
你说得对，不要一直说话 破坏了这美好安详的一刻
You're right, Bob. Let's not spoil the beauty of this moment...
有些人就是爱碎碎念
...with idle chatter.
对牛弹琴弹到牛都不想听了
Some people can just jibber-jabber till the cows come home.
这是什么意思啊？ “对牛弹琴”
What does that mean, Bob? "Till the cows come home."
牛会听音乐吗？
Where have the cows been?
听好，森林小学第一课
Okay, Forest 101.
那一根根高大的木头叫做树木
These big wood stick things are called trees.
超巨大的岩石叫做山 那些小石头是山的宝宝
The big rocks are called mountains, and the little rocks are their babies.
惧高症
Altitude.
不能软脚，不能软脚 加油
No jelly arm, no jelly arm. Come on.
-爱鹿特 -布谷侠，这…
- Elliot! - Boogster, it's...
要我说多少遍你才了解
How many times must I say it?
我叫做超人特攻鹿
I am the Incredible Mister E.
救我
Elliot, please.
天啊，如果你不用化名叫我的话
Look, if you don't use the code names...
我怎么知道 在跟我说话的到底是不是你啊！
...how am I supposed to know that it's really you that I'm talking to?
没事…没问题了
Yeah, yeah. Okay, I got it.
轻轻的，慢慢来
Nice and easy.
你就给我一个痛快，快拔吧
Just rip it off fast, like a Band-Aid.
乖乖不要动，好吗？
Hold still, okay?
你冷静一点，可能会有点痛
Just be calm. This might pinch a little.
-快拔啦 -我劝你最好捂住耳朵
- Get it over with. - You may wanna cover your ears.
捂住什么…？
Cover my--?
好了，快窜回森林里去吧，兄弟
Okay, scamper on back to the woods, little buddy.
兄弟
Buddy.
听好，你们这些娘们 老天不会帮你们盖水
Okay, ladies, this dam ain't gonna build itself!
抬起桦树，把那批松木弄过来
Lift that birch. Swing those pines over here.
快，动作快
Come on. Move it!
阿土
Yo, O'Toole!
-是，老大 -我要你把柏木呈斜角方向
- Yeah, boss? - I want you to cantilever that cedar...
固定在北端的横梁上 懂不懂啊？
...on the bias down by the north end, you got that?
把木梢插进去
Put a twig in the hole.
菜鸟
Rookie.
放饭时间五分钟
Take five for lunch!
-你吃什么？ -木头
- What do you got? - Wood.
要交换吗？
You wanna trade?
兄弟们，你们看
Hey, hey, guys. Check it out.
那是北美体型最大的肉食性动物
There goes the largest carnivore in North America.
-最威猛的大熊 -同时他还是舞王
- The mighty grizzly. - And he's a good dancer.
我们有自己的秀
We're gonna be in a show.
走了啦
Come here!
我只剩这根鹿角了
Hey, that's my good antler.
听好，呆头 没有所谓的我们，只有我
Listen, simple. We are not "we."
而我们不会一起作秀
It's just me. And we ain't doing no show.
-大牌 -什么？
- Diva. - What?
我了解现在什么状况了
I understand what's going on here.
你这么气嘟嘟是因为你饿了
You're a little crabby because you're hungry.
我…
I, I...
我不会错的
I think yes.
我饿得快死了
I'm starving!
-来，试试看 -我不才吃素里
- Here, try this. - I can't eat that.
挑食、挑嘴、偏食
Picky, picky, picky.
不然熊都吃什么？
Well, what do bears eat?
吃鱼，熊是吃鱼的
Fish. Bears eat fish.
好了，鱼儿们，过来喂饱布谷
All right, fishies, give it up for Boog!
你讲啥？ 阿搭妈秀斗…
超人特攻鹿
Hey, Incredible Mister E.
什么事？布谷侠
Yes, Boogster?
-我要嗯嗯 -那就…嗯啊
- I gotta go. - Well, go.
不行，我需要马桶啦
No, I need a toilet.
就是蛋糕盆…方便坑
You know, the think tank.
霜淇淋洞，堆…堆肥水池
The log cabin, the johnny on the spot, the oval office.
-荒郊野外没有那些东西 -那你都怎么嗯？
- There's none of those things out here. - Well, what do you do?
我都是…
You know...
就地取材 你听我说
...I can't remember. But listen.
不要想太多 你看那地方有个小树丛，是你专属的
Don't look now, but I see a little bush with your name written all over it.
小树丛，别闹了啦
A bush? Are you serious?
就像骑独轮车一样简单
Go on. It's just like riding a bicycle.
只要…习惯就好
Only you're crapping on it.
秀出你的嗯嗯脸，狂野小子
Show us your "grr" face, nature boy.
喂，你们看什么？
Hey. What are you doing here?
走开啦
Get out of here.
我正在嗯嗯 走开
I'm working here. Now, go.
好啦…你们玩够了
All right, all right, you've had your fun.
没什么好看的，让大熊做大蛋糕
Nothing to see here. Let the bear do his thing.
这有什么好看的？
You believe those guys?
嗯完没？
Finished?
我敢打赌那大胖子一定嗯不出来
I bet my nuts that big hairy choob can't do it.
-我跟你一样赌他嗯不出来 -你们这些动物都有什么毛病？
- I'll take a piece of that action. - What is wrong with you animals?
给他灌肠吧，兄弟
Perhaps some roughage, buddy?
兄弟
Buddy.
给我一点隐私好不好？
Perhaps some privacy.
-你跑到我家来冲啥？ -这是你家？
- What are doing on my house? - This is your house?
我…我不知道
Oh, I-- I didn't know...
-你家可能较漂亮哦 -你在说什么五四三
- It would be an improvement. - What did you just say, Rosie?
没有啦，你干嘛这么神经质
Nothing. Why you gotta be so sensitive?
-布谷侠，你在磨蹭什么？ -你嘴巴放干净一点
- Boogster, what's the deal? - You watch your mouth...
不然我会让你看不到明天的日头
...or you'll get yourself in trouble.
你就是眼红 偶有男人疼惜啦
You're just jealous because you ain't got a man.
有两个赤扒扒在吵架
I don't know. Some kind of chick fight.
爱鹿特，我该怎么办
Elliot, what do I do?
这个简单 你只要划出你的地盘
Well, that's easy. You just gotta mark your territory.
-告诉她们谁是老大 -好了，小姐们
- Show them who's boss. - All right, ladies.
现在由我当家
I'm laying down the law.
当然碰到臭鼬就快闭嘴
Unless, of course, they're skunks.
臭牟牟
Disgusting.
吉赛儿
Giselle.
太夸张了
Ridiculous.
整座森林居然容不下一头熊
The woods is no place for a bear.
鸭子
Ducks? Okay.
不要动
Look, don't move.
好个移花接木
Oh, yeah. Sprucing up.
快，你们一定要帮我
Quick. You guys gotta help me.
不要怪丹尼，先生 他有一点紧张
Don't mind Deni, monsieur. He's a bit nervous.
他从来没有…怎么说呢？
Never been quite...
正常过 自从大迁徙以后他就这样了
...right since the great migration.
我们好几千只野鸭子 排成V字飞行中队
There were thousands of us when we started in the big V's.
后来…太可怕，就出事了
Then... Then it happened.
出了什么事了？
What happened?
什么事？ 打猎季节开始了
What happened? Open season happened.
只有我跟丹尼活下来
Just me and Deni were left.
两只鸭子怎么排成V字飞行中队？
How can you make a V with only two duck, you ask, eh?
根本就不可能嘛
Well, you cannot, monsieur.
真是太悲惨了
It's a tragedy!
对…好惨
Yeah, right, whatever.
是这样子的，我要回村里
But check this out. I'm looking for town.
能不能请你们飞到天上去
Okay? Now, could one of you guys fly up there...
-帮我带个路？ -飞行…飞行
- ...and show me the way? - Fly? Fly?
别吵，他会听到
Quiet. They'll hear you.
吉赛儿
Giselle.
-爱鹿特 -小美人，你好吗？
- Elliot? - Hey, gorgeous.
爱鹿特，你跑哪去了？
- How you doing? - Elliot, where have you been?
我去…大城市
Oh, you know. Big city.
闯盆江湖，增广见闻 大鱼大肉，作秀爆红
Kind of a road trip. Saw the sights, hit the buffet, took in a show.
前途一片光明
Things are looking up, Giselle.
真的？听说你被卡车撞了
Really? I heard you got hit by a truck.
那是谣言
That-- Rumor.
你最好快点溜 还记得你上次
You better get out of here. Remember what happened...
-跟我说话死得有多难看？ -伊恩在附近？
- ...last time you talked to me? - Is Ian around?
你这样抽搐多久了？
How long have you had that tic?
越来越恶化了
I think it's getting worse.
糗大了
Oh, crud.
你好啊，臭鹿特
Hello, "Smelliot."
我都叫他臭鹿特
I called him Smelliot.
兄弟们，正圆围攻阵
Herd! Circle formation!
群天兵，那是椭圆
You pinheads. That's an oval.
再…圆一点
More circle-y!
你还真有种敢回来这里
You got a lot of nerve coming back here.
-谢谢夸奖 -我不是在夸奖你，孬种
- Why, thank you. - That was not a compliment, maggot!
他正要离开了 对吧，爱鹿特
Well, he was just going. Right, Elliot?
对…伊恩
Yeah, Ian.
我…我只是顺道过来 跟几个老朋友打个招呼
I had to stop by and say hello to some of my old pals.
包伯、凯文、席丹 额头好点没？
Bob, Kevin. Jurgen, how's the knee?
我将你逐出家门 永远…
I told you to leave the herd and never, ever, ever...
-永远？ -永远…永远不准回来
- Never? - Never, ever, ever come back.
回来？
Back?
我没…没要回来
I'm not-- I'm not back.
我…我和我的好哥儿们要去山林村
Me and my best buddy are heading to town.
对啊，我一定会想念你们的
Yeah. I sure am gonna miss you guys.
放开你的臭蹄子
Off the upholstery!
又怎么了？
What now?
就像我刚才说的，永远…
So as I was saying, never, ever, ever--
熊…
A bear! Bear. Bear. A bear.
爱鹿特，你还好吧？
Elliot, are you all right?
头昏昏，脑钝钝
Buttermilk biscuit.
伊恩，他还背娃娃耶
Hey, Ian. Get a load of this.
快住手
Hey, cut it out.
我听过你哦
Oh, I've heard of you.
你是被松鼠K得满头包的大笨熊
You're that bear that got his butt thumped by a squirrel.
他们有好几百只耶
It was-- There was 20 of them.
他们还有松果耶
And they had nuts.
不要理他，布谷
Don't listen to him, Boog.
布谷？ 是什么鬼名字？
Boog? What is that short for?
-布谷鸟吗？ -布谷鸟
- Booger? - Booger!
-给我听好 -我是在听啊
- Listen, you! - I'm all ears.
-我…这个… -布谷，我们走啦
- Well... - Boog, let's go.
你们两个真是天生的绝配
You two are perfect for each other.
你是衰ㄎㄚ，而你是大西瓜
You're a loser and you're a loser-er.
兄弟们，我们走
Herd, let's bound!
臭鹿特
Hey, Elliot.
你的那根掉了哦
I think you lost something.
也许会长回来的，拜，爱鹿特
Maybe it'll grow back. Bye, Elliot.
拜了
Yeah, see you.
后会有期了，大胖熊宝宝
See you later, backpack boy!
这就对了，叫你落跑吧
That's right, fool. You better run.
跑远一点啊，没种的娘娘腔
Keep on prancing, you panty-waisted cow.
对，他再废话，我就要开扁了
Yeah. One more word, and I was gonna rack him.
-没错 -我超想扁他，你看看他
- That's right. - I was waiting for it.
吓死了，吓得屁滚尿流
He's scared. He's scared.
对啊，就是啊
- Look at him run. Look at him run. - Yeah, I know it.
放他一马吧
Look at him go.
你请他喝一杯前要不要亲他一下？
Are you not gonna buy him a drink before you kiss him?
你们这对好姐妹
You big jessie.
给我滚啦，衰ㄎㄚ，大西瓜
On your bikes, you big numpties.
刚才那是伊恩的女友，你想把她？
That was Ian's girl you was trying to talk to, huh?
小色鬼
You dog.
他说得对，我是个衰ㄎㄚ
Ian's right. I'm a loser.
-你才不是衰ㄎㄚ -明明就是
- No, you're not a loser. - Yes, I am.
-你不是 -我是
- No, you're not. - Yes.
相信我 遇见你那天，伊恩把我赶出家门
Trust me. You know the day I met you, Ian kicked me out of the herd.
鹿角断了一根，被车撞昏 还被人绑在引擎盖上
I lost my antler, I got run over and tied to the hood of a truck.
你说那叫什么？
What do you call that?
衰ㄎㄚ… 那我呢？
A loser. But check this out.
掌声欢迎最威猛的大熊
Behold, the mighty grizzly.
我长得像熊，说话像熊
I look like a bear, I talk like a bear.
我却不会抓鱼，也不会爬树 连待在森林都不会
But I can't fish, I can't climb a tree, I can't even go in the woods.
那算什么？ 我像驴，又像鹿，我四不像
That's nothing. Half doe. Half buck. I'm a duck.
我骑着独轮车跟人要饼干
Hey, I ride a unicycle for crackers!
-我眼袋很大 -我不会弹手指
- I have a glass eye. - I can't snap.
-我以为手机是鸡 -我胖到看不到小弟弟
- I thought "log" was a color. - I can't see my feet.
人是我杀的
I killed a man.
至少你还有家可以回
Well, at least you've got a home.
家…
Home. Yeah.
但愿回得了家
I sure hope so.
-这什么声音，你的脖子吗？ -不是
- Crimenently! Was that your neck? - No.
我的小鱼饼干，她还是爱我的
My fishy crackers. Oh, she still loves me.
谢谢你，贝丝
Thank you, Beth.
我要回去！
I'm coming home.
吃吧，哥儿们
Try one, partner. Yeah.
虽然没有哇塞棒好吃 但可安慰你
Woo Hoo bars they ain't, but they take you back.
让你想到家的温暖
You know? Remind you of home.
甜甜咸咸的家
Sweet, salty home.
可以回到又软又蓬松的床上
Oh, yeah. To be back in my own soft bed.
一天可以吃八餐，外加点心
Eight square meals a day, plus snacks.
贝丝每晚都可以哄我入睡
Beth tucking me in every night.
那里是我的天堂
It's like heaven to me.
对了…明天一回到村里
You know, when we get back home tomorrow...
我一定会跟贝丝和好如初
...I'm gonna make things right with Beth.
也许只是也许
And maybe, just maybe...
可以在车库里弄个地方让你窝着
...we'll find a place for you in the garage with me.
赞啦 我要车库
Sweet! Oh, yeah. I'm in the garage.
谁要车库… 我要车库，就是我
Who's staying in the garage? I'm in the garage.
Who's got a place in the garage? It's me. Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah--
-哥儿们 -啥事啊？
- Hey, buddy? - Yeah?
帮个忙好不好 我有一点不太好意思说
Do me a favor, will you? It's gonna sound silly, but will you--?
-你可以…算了 -快说啦
- Ah, forget it. - What?
快说啦，我挺你，老哥
Come on. I'm here for you.
你…你可以唱一下 “泰迪熊野餐”给我听吗？
Will you sing me that "teddy-bear picnic" song?
当然…可以，什么歌？
Absolutely. The what song?
贝丝每天都会唱给我听的 她一唱我就睡着了
Well, Beth always sings it to me, you know, because it helps me sleep.
-好吧，那我就来试试看 -谢啦
- Okay. I'll give it a shot. - Thanks.
从前有个神秘矮人 他住在彩虹树里
Once there was a magical elf Who lived in a rainbow tree
他楼上住着便秘侏儒
He lived downstairs From a flatulent dwarf
每天都对楼下放屁
Who was constantly having to pee
有天矮人受不了了
One day the elf could take no more
跑到楼上敲侏儒的门
So he went and banged On the rude dwarf's door
结果没想到他们居然公证结婚
And what do you know They suddenly both were married
晚安，布谷
Good night, Boog.
我有车库可以睡了 我要睡在车库里
I'm sleeping in the garage. I'm sleeping in the garage.
快啊，腊肠先生 你做得到哦，加油
Come on, Mr. Weenie. Beg. You can do it.
加油，拜拜
Come on. Beg.
巴伯他不听话 巴伯教他怎么拜拜
Bob, he won't listen. Bob, show him how to beg.
是拜狗教徒
Dog worship.
妈啊
Oh, my!
-你们没事吧？ -什么？不…
- You folks all right? - What? No, no, no! He's--
他绑架了你们，我知道…
Taken you hostage. I know, I know.
你们获救了，我制伏了敌人
You're safe now. I've got the enemy neutral--
好了，腊肠先生 没事了，宝贝
There, there, Mr. Weenie. Are you all right, baby?
你是天底下最可爱的腊肠狗
You're the sweetest little weenie I ever saw.
不要再傻了，他们是一伙的
Don't be fooled. He's one of them.
-谁？ -敌人啊，笨熊、笨鹿
- Who? - The enemy! The bear! That deer!
所有的动物
All them animals!
我已经预见未来了
I have seen the future.
就从山林村这种小镇开始肆虐
It will start in small towns like Timberline.
很快就天下大乱
Soon, it'll spread.
所有的动物全部倾巢而出 从洞穴、动物园
They will invade from burrows, caves, petting zoos.
如果我不阻止他们
If I don't stop them...
人类就要被他们踩在脚下了
...it'll be a total reversal of the natural order.
他们会嘲笑我无能 等着瞧吧
They laugh at old Shaw, but you'll see.
真相早晚会大白的
The truth will be revealed.
我们听懂你的话了
We know exactly what you mean.
-真的？ -我们是科学家，可以算是吧
- You do? - We're scientists. Well, of sorts.
我们想要拍栩栩如生的纪录片
And we're trying to secure photographic documentation...
拍活生生的野生大人猿
...of a real, live homo-sasquatchus.
-野…野生什么？ -我们要去找大脚怪
- Homo-say-what? - We're looking for Bigfoot.
大脚… 我居然跟两个头壳坏掉疯子哈啦
Bigfoot--? I didn't realize I was talking to a couple of wack jobs.
不要相信他 宠物是双面间谍
Don't trust him. Pets are double agents.
只要你稍不注意 他就会咬你
The moment you turn your back, he'll shiv you!
不可能，我们收服他了
Oh, no, he can't. We had him fixed.
布谷
Boog?
布谷，你醒了吗？
Boog. Are you awake?
-现在醒了 -太好了
- I am now. - Awesome.
我昨晚看到你的睡相了耶 你就像个小天使
I was watching you sleep last night and you were like a little angel.
不过你太胖，打呼声好像…
Except for you're fat and snoring like:
我会帮你解决问题的
We're gonna work on that, though.
我发明了打呼疗法 把整只手
I invented this cure where you stick your whole hand...
-塞进嘴巴里就好了 -要多久才能回到山林村？
- ...in your mouth. - How long before we get to Timberline?
天黑以前，安啦
Oh, by nightfall. Easy.
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
当然确定了
Absolutely.
想不想看我搞笑？
Hey, you wanna see something stupid?
我觉得我们最好快点赶路
Well, then we better get going.
对，我们要赶时间 这个我帮你保管
Right. We're on a tight schedule. I'll carry your load.
不…等等
Oh, no. Whoa, wait.
你最好小心一点，不要弄掉了 因为他是很脆弱的
Look, you gotta be real careful with him, okay, because he's real delicate.
想吃小鱼饼干吗？
Want a fishy cracker?
不想，回家再吃好了
No. I'll eat when I get home.
听着，好姐妹
Listen, girlfriend.
想要找到像偶男朋友那种男子汉 就要打扮得漂亮一点
You wanna find a man like my Ignacio, you gotta check your look.
黑白讲，偶美得冒泡 我可以把到所有的男子汉
What are you saying? I'm black and white. I go with everything.
问题出在所有的男子汉 都不想把你
You go fine with everybody. Maybe that's your problem.
-那不是昨天那两只臭到爆的 -我有几个作秀好点子
- Ain't those the same two skunks-- - I had some thoughts on the show.
-我的秀？ -热裤妞过时了
- My show? - The lady in the shorts has gotta go.
她是票房毒药 节目要够酷、够炫、热情够劲
She's slowing us down. It's gotta be fresh, new. I want some jazz.
我才是主秀 观众买票是来看我的
I'm the star, and the people out there come to see me...
威猛大熊
...a grizzly bear.
原来如此
I see.
你有你的事业 我就得待在家里照顾小布丁
You get to have the career while I stay home and look after Dinkleman!
我又不是你老婆
He's not even mine!
我就不能去追逐梦想，是不是？
I don't get to have a dream. Is that it?
兄弟
Buddy.
你有没有想过 也许我喜欢唱歌
Don't you think I might like a little singing...
-喜欢跳舞，来点… -爱鹿特
- ...a little dancing, a little: - Elliot.
没有嘛，你只会一直问我 “要多久才能回到山林村？呆头”
But no. All I ever hear is, "How long until we get to Timberline, simple?
-“要多少才能…” -爱鹿特，那是同一群水獭吗？
- How long until we get home?" - Elliot! Are those the same beavers?
-不是，水獭长得都一样 -青蛙王子
- No. All beavers look alike. - Hey! Tiny dancer!
好耶，摇咧摇咧…
Yeah, that's right! Shake it, shake it!
-秀给我们看嘛 -爱鹿特
- Let's see some moves! - Elliot!
干嘛？
Yeah.
爱鹿特，又是那一座带衰水 我们一直在绕圈子
Elliot, this is the same dang dam. We've been going in circles!
圈子，一次绕一圈
Circle. One time around.
你根本就不知道哪里是哪里
You don't even know where we're going.
帅啊，箩琳
Got them, Lorraine!
-那是什么 -猎人
- What was that? - Hunters?
-他们跑来上游干嘛？ -好了，兄弟们，找掩护
- What are they doing up here? - Okay, boys. Take cover!
-布谷，快躲起来 -我先走一步
- Boog, we gotta hide. - I'm out of here.
布谷，等等，不要踩上去
Boog, wait! Don't go out there!
大胖子，你站住 你那么大一只会踩垮水蔚睦
Hey, tubby, stop! Hey, this ain't a load-bearing structure!
糗爆了
Oh, that's bad.
箩西，快躲起来
Rosie, in here.
-走开，放手 -兄弟…
- Stop. Get off. - Buddy, buddy, buddy!
惨了
Crud.
煞星
Shaw!
小布丁
Dinkleman!
你不会有事的
You're gonna be okay!
我们死定了，你明知道的
We're gonna die and you know it.
这一次没有人能够救得了你们了
No one around here to save you this time, boys!
划，布谷，快划
Paddle, Boog! Paddle!
前面有大石头…
Grab a boulder! Grab a boulder!
左边…右边
Left, left. Right!
你好神哦
Oh, like you know.
他人呢
Where is he?
不见了 又见了
He's gone. Oh, there he is.
No, wait. There he is. There he is.
-你这个小王八… -他在那里
- Why, you little-- - There he is.
别吵，我在驾驶
Quiet, I'm trying to drive.
快点，布谷
Faster, Boog!
这好像一边打猎一边钓鱼
Like fishing and hunting at the same time.
-拉我一把，布谷快抱住我，布谷 -放开我，爱鹿特
- Give me a hand, Boog! Hold me! - Stop. Get off! Elliot, get off. Get off!
停！
Stop!
小布丁
Dinkleman?
你…都是你害的
You. You did this.
-对，没错… -什么，我怎么了？
- Yeah, that's right. - What did I do?
你把我们冲到打猎特区来了
You dragged us down to the hunting grounds.
-你要我们躲去哪里？ -我们是煮熟的鸭子了
- Yeah, where are we gonna hide? - We're sitting ducks out here.
猎季就要开始了
And it's open season!
对… 好了…不要吵了
All right, all right. That's enough.
这不能都怪他
Guys, it's not his fault.
没错，爱鹿特，这都要怪你
Oh, you're right, Elliot. It's your fault.
-怪我？ -对
- My fault? - Yeah.
要不是你 我现在就会待在家里
If it weren't for you I'd be home right now.
这一切就不会发生
None of this would've ever happened.
你还说你知道回去的路 可是你耍我
You said you knew the way back, but you lied.
我…没有
I-- No.
好啦
Okay.
好啦，也许
Okay, maybe--
我以为只要我们混在一起 你就会喜欢我
I thought if you hung out with me then maybe you would like me.
天啊，亏我这么相信你
Oh, man. I trusted you, Elliot.
对不起，布谷，我…
I'm sorry, Boog.
还是好哥儿们，对吗？
We're still partners, right?
不必了，我还是自己走吧
You know, Elliot, I'm better off alone.
那我们呢？
What about us?
-对啊，那我们呢？ -别这样嘛…
- Yeah. - Yeah, what about us?
我们？什么我们？
Us? There's no us.
那是你家的事 至于你，我们完了
You're not my problem. And you? We're done.
-可是，布谷，等等 -完了
- But-- Boog, wait. - Done.
-不 -谢谢你发照给我，戈帝
- Oh, no. - Thanks for the license, Gordy.
好了，祝你们好运
All right, guys. Good luck.
-厄尔，新车啊？ -对啊，怎么样，羡慕嫉妒？
- Hey, Earl. That a new truck? - Yeah. Check it out. Jealous much?
你还好吧
You okay?
我把他送去瀑布上游
I put him way above the falls.
但愿我这么做是对的
I hope I did the right thing.
你放心，贝丝 布谷待在新家会很快乐的
Don't worry, Beth. I'm sure Boog is happy in his new home.
讨厌的大自然
Stupid nature.
文明世界
Civilization.
有人吗？
Hello?
对不起，打扰了 请问有人在吗？
Excuse me. Is anybody home?
心爱的蛋糕盆
Oh, sweet porcelain.
观众也为他疯狂
And the crowd goes wild!
这屋子里一定会有冰箱
Now, there's gotta be a fridge in here somewhere.
哇塞
喔，不
Oh, no.
笨鹿、臭鼬、水獭
Deers, skunks, beavers.
快躲起来
I gotta hide.
全被那只笨熊给带坏了
That bear's turned them all.
坐一下，宝贝箩琳 舒服的休息吧
Here you go, Lorraine. There, you get good and dry.
一大早我们还要去打击犯罪呢
Come morning, we got a rebellion to crush.
然后夺回属于我的一切
And then I'm gonna take back what's mine!
爱鹿特
Elliot.
有人吃掉了我的糖
Someone's been eating my candy.
有人坐过了我的椅子
Somebody's been sitting in my chair.
有人忘了冲马桶
Somebody forgot to flush!
他现在还在这里
And he's still here.
来找你的小矮人啊，白雪公主
Come back for your bear, Goldilocks?
你完蛋，因为我来了
Ready or not, here I come!
如果你今天跑进森林 会碰到个大惊喜
If you go out in the woods today You're sure of a big surprise
如果你今天跑进森林 你最好伪装自己
If you go out in the woods today You better go in disguise
因为森林里每一只熊
'Cause every bear That ever there was
都会在这里聚在一起
Was gathered there Together because
因为今天是熊宝宝的
Today's the day The teddy bears have
野餐日
Their picnic!
笨熊，你绝对逃不出我的手掌心
Hey, bear! There ain't nowhere that you can hide from me!
只要我弄到我的…
As soon as I get mine:
带头的开快一点
Blowing their heads off!
打猎最好玩了
Good time.
爱鹿特
Elliot.
兄弟没了
No buddy.
爱鹿特，快躲起来
Elliot, you've gotta hide.
猎人来了
The hunters are here.
他会害死我们的
He's gonna give us away.
啊，来啊，谁怕谁
All right! Bring it! Bring it!
-布谷 -哥儿们
- Boog? - Hey, buddy.
你跑回来做什么？
What are you doing back here?
拜托，没有好哥儿们我回不了家
Come on. I couldn't go home without my partner.
-我才没有哥儿们 -爱鹿特
- I don't have a partner. - Elliot.
我不需要鹿群，我也不需要你
I don't need the herd and I don't need you.
不要来烦我
So leave me alone.
这点我可能做不到
Ain't gonna be able to do it.
因为我已经救了你一命
You see, I already saved you once.
我要负起责任来…保护你
That makes me responsible for you.
别装了 我要你亲口说“好哥儿们”
I saw that. Come on. Let me hear you say it. Partners.
-不要 -你说什么？
- No. - What was that?
-我们可以做好哥儿们 -抱歉，我听不见
- I guess we can be partners. - Sorry, I can't hear you.
我说我们可以做好哥儿们
I said I guess we can be partners.
-好哥儿们… -好哥儿们…
- Partners! - Partners!
走这边
Okey-dokey. This way.
-走这边 -对，换你带路好了
- This way. - Right. Maybe you better lead.
好，只要回到车库我们就安全了
Yeah. Let's get back to the garage, where it's safe.
-安全？ -安全？
- Safe? - Safe?
布谷 你车库里可以挤得下多少动物？
Hey, Boog. How many animals can fit in the garage?
多少动…
How many--?
嗨，布谷…
Hello, Boog.
请问… 你们要去哪？
So where you all headed?
-安全的地方 -安全的圣地…车库
- To the safe place. - This land of garage.
-跟兄弟 -哥儿们，你欠我们一份情
- With buddy. - Come on. You owe us, Tiny.
-对啊，没错… -是啊
- Yeah! - Yeah! That's right!
对不起，我毁了水
Yeah, I'm sorry about the dam.
把你们都害得这么惨 对不起，是我的错
And how I messed you all up, you know. My bad.
听着，你要带我们一起走，布谷鸟
So you're taking us with you, right, Booger?
拜托，我求求你
Please? Please.
看看我 我长太帅，死了可惜啊
Look at me. I'm too pretty to die!
这个嘛…也许
Well, maybe...
不行…不可以…
No! No! No!
你不能丢下偶们
You ain't leaving without us.
我不会再叫你布谷鸟
I didn't mean to call you Booger.
-兄弟，可以带吉赛儿去好吗？ -等一等…让我想一想
- Can we take Giselle? - Wait! Let me think.
猎人
Hunters.
可恶，今天晚上谁都别想回家了
Dang. Nobody's going home tonight.
他们人太多了
There's so many of them.
这下死定了
That's it, then.
我要死了
No more me.
我的头要挂在墙壁上了
I guess I will be mounted on a wall.
放心，你不会
Oh, no, you won't.
如果我变成了熊皮地毯 也许会让人践踏
Now, when I'm a bearskin rug, they can walk all over me.
可是我现在还活着 我要跟他们拼了，绝不投降
But until that happens, I ain't going out without a fight.
-什么…？ -他说什么…？
- What? - Fight?
-他糊涂了 -没错
- The F word? - That's right.
这就是你们教会我的一件事
One thing you all have taught me...
这座森林危机四伏，危险得要命
...the woods is a messed-up, dangerous place.
你们超疯狂的 这两天你们把我整得超惨的
And y'all are crazy. You've been kicking my butt for the last two days.
对啊，有一点
Yeah, I kind of did.
不好意思
- I didn't. - Sorry.
你们要用对我的招数 对付他们
So let's do to them what you've been doing to me.
让我们的敌人享受 全套的大自然体验
Now, I say we give our guests the full outdoor experience.
万岁！
Yeah!
你想要单打独斗，还是全体大作战？
Hey! Is this a private fight or can anybody join?
因为我妙酷鼠想要参一脚
Because McSquizzy wants in.
很好，我们需要你们的胆量
Good. Because we'll need your nuts.
-还有你们的松果 -你有什么计划，布谷？
- And your acorns too. - What's the plan, Boog?
我们要把那些野人赶回村里
Oh, we gonna run those yahoos back to town.
对，没错 把他们整死，再也不敢乱来
Yeah, baby. When we get through with them, they won't ever come back.
你以为你很厉害
So you think you're so tough, huh?
你给我听好
Well, you know what I think?
在我眼里你只是熊宝宝
I think you're still just a mama's bear.
你负责留守，腊肠先生 妈咪要去凉一下
You guard the fort, Mr. Weenie. Mama's gonna take a dip.
太好了，我都快被她醺死了
That's good. Mama's getting kind of gamey.
快点，巴伯 今晚的月亮好圆好亮哦
Come on, Bob. There's gonna be a full moon out tonight.
-抱歉 -快点，走了
- Sorry. - Come on. Let's go.
布谷
Boog?
好耶
Oh, yeah.
-犸莉亚，放手啦 -给偶啦
- Maria, let go. - I'll carry it.
空的啦
It's empty.
女人哦
Ladies.
一、二… 一、二…
Heave-ho, heave-ho.
哈哈！好戏上场
This is gonna be great.
我们需要更多的鸭子
You. We gonna need more ducks.
爱鹿特，你脸上的是哇塞吗？
Elliot, is that chocolate on your face?
不是
No.
-宠物 -他会害我们失败
- It's a pet. - He's gonna blow our cover.
我活得毫无意义
I've been living a lie!
求求你们带我走
Please, take me with you.
布谷，你不会还在气我 笑你背娃娃的事吧？
Hey, Boog. You're not still mad about that backpack thing, are you?
安啦，我早就忘光光了 凡事要放开点
Oh, no. I never hold a grudge. I just let them go.
什么声音
What was that?
是攻击信号
It's the signal.
好了，丹尼，赶鸭子上架
Okay, Deni. Let's round them up!
好了，姐妹们，屁弹攻势
All right, ladies. Let her rip!
-戴防毒罩 -收到
- Gas mask. - Got it!
我的裤子
My pants!
干得好，莱利 好了
Good job, Reilly. All right.
把这些野人赶回村里去
Time to run these guys back to town.
准备好让我骑了吗？
Are you ready for this?
-这个…有点糗耶 -没错，你说得对
- This is awkward. - Yes. Yes, it is.
-让我来 -一切就看你的了
- Can I? - Go for it, Smelliot.
冲啊
Charge!
万兽大狂奔，妈妈咪啊
Holy stampede! It's a stampede!
现在秀出你们超酷的表情
All right. Show me your "grr" face!
一起来恶整臭猎人吧
Now, let's kick some hunter bahookie!
巴伯，我们被抢了
Bob, we've been robbed!
他们掳走了腊肠先生
And they took Mr. Weenie!
不要退缩，向前冲啊 杀他个片甲不留
Come on, mate! Move them pudgy wee legs!
人生充满了意义
I feel so alive!
上鹿角刺刀
Drop antlers!
祝福我
Bless me.
不要…
No! No!
怎样啊，哥儿们
How you doing, partner?
这真是太劲爆了 我们每年都来一次吧
Boog, this is great. Let's do this every year.
不…不要，不要再咬我了 走开
No, no! Get that bill away from me.
发射…
Fire!
兄弟们，快逃命啊
Guys, let's get out of here!
警长
Sheriff! Sheriff!
动物抓狂了 那头熊带头造反了
The animals are going wild, and the bear is their leader!
找你的
It's for you.
戈帝，我去带他回来
Gordy, I'm bringing him home.
怕什么，他们不过是畜牲嘛
Come on, men! They're just animals.
爱鹿特，接着
Elliot, catch.
接到了
Got it.
大火攻
Present arms!
耶…！
Yeah!
发射
Fire!
天啊
Oh, my God!
快回到车上去
Back to the trucks!
布谷，成功了
Boog, it's working.
全落跑了
Yeah. Look at them run.
-祭出爆爆先生 -谁？
- Send in Mr. Happy! - Who?
冲…
Go, go, go!
投弹
Adieu!
爆爆先生没有爆爆
Mr. Happy didn't go off.
我们只是要赶他们走而已
Hey, whoa. We're just supposed to run them into town.
没错啦，那些人早该落跑了 你说对不对？
Well, it's time for them to start running, isn't it?
厄尔，那不是你的新车吗？
Hey, Earl, ain't that your truck?
现在不是了
That's a bummer.
对啦…继续跑
That's right. Keep running.
赞啦
Sweet.
自由无价
Freedom!
你好，大笨熊
Hello, Goldilocks.
什么？
What?
漂亮啦
Bull's-eye!
快，需要弹药补给
Quick! We need more ammo.
爱鹿特，不要鸡婆了
Elliot! Elliot, stop helping me.
-继续补给 -好，看你喜不喜欢被K
- Keep it coming. - Okay. Let's see how you like it.
枕头，拜托
A pillow? Oh, come on!
再来…
More! More!
够了
All right.
来啊，熊宝贝
Come on, mama's bear.
你可以再狠一点，使出绝招来
You can do better than that. Let's see what you got.
来啊
Come on.
布谷
Boog!
帅，谁叫你惹毛布谷，一杆进…
Oh, yeah. Don't mess with the Boogster. Fore!
耶，宝贝箩琳
All right, Lorraine.
亲亲熊宝宝说晚安吧！
Let's kiss this bear good night.
不…不要
No! No! Stop!
爱鹿特
Elliot?
哥儿们
Buddy?
爱鹿特
Oh, Elliot.
爱鹿特，没事吧？
You all right, Elliot?
头有点轻飘飘
I'm a little lightheaded.
威猛大熊，漂亮哦
Hey, Tiny. Nice show.
-布谷… -掌声欢迎最威猛的
- Behold, the mighty grizzly. - Boog, Boog, Boog.
-海扁他 -不要
- Let's get him! - What? No!
-走开，不… -去死吧
- Stay away! No! - Here you go.
万箭穿心
Cannonball!
其实爱鹿特，这个地方满不赖的
You know, Elliot, this place ain't so bad.
等我一下
Hold that thought. Oh, yeah.
看我的佛山无影脚
Karate noises!
不
No.
-贝丝 -布谷
- Beth? - Boog?
布谷
Oh, Boog.
-他在干嘛？ -他没有要海扁她
- What's he doing? - Is he not gonna maul her?
没，她是布谷妈 她会把我们带回家
No. She's his mom. She's taking us home.
全部带走？
Every buddy?
我好担心你哦 我要带你回家去
I was so worried. I'm bringing you back with me.
走，我们回家
Come on. Let's go home.
不
Oh, no.
来啊，布谷，回家！
Come on, Boog. Let's go home.
布谷？
Boog?
你已经到家了
You are home.
你让我觉得好骄傲
I'm so proud of you.
怎么样，直升机应该可以 载得下我们两个吧
So how are we both gonna fit in the helicopter?
-她还会再回来吧 -谁？
- She's coming back, right? - Who?
热裤妞啊 布谷
The shorts lady. Boog?
-大个儿 -你好，小不点
- Hey, big guy. - What's up, Tiny?
-好极了 -你说过要…
- What's up? - You said that we--
-你不爽偶吗？ -你们好吗？
- You're judging me? - How y'all doing?
嗨，布谷你…
- Hey, Boog. - Hi, Boog.
虽然他素只鸭子 可素他很疼偶
I know he's a duck. But he treats me like a lady.
-可是她… -兄弟
- But she's-- - Hey, buddy.
-帮我找点吃的 -别闹了，她什么时候来接我们？
- Hey, find me some food. - Come on. What is our pickup time?
爱鹿特，我们要留下来 这里是我们的家
Elliot, we're staying here. This is our home.
他们超哈我们的 这里才是我们的地盘
These are our people. This is where we reside.
什么？你秀逗啦
What? Are you insane?
这两天发生的事你都忘了吗？
Where have you been for the last two days?
这地方太恐怖了，太可怕了
This place is horrible. Horrible!
-哥儿们 -什么事，伊恩
- Hey, guys. - What's up, Ian?
好了，爱鹿特，没那么糟
Come on, Elliot. It ain't that bad.
起码她… 她应该会送一堆哇塞棒过来对吧
She's at least gonna bring some Woo Hoo bars, right?
就剩我们哥儿们了，爱鹿特
It's just the two of us, Elliot.
除非你想回到你的鹿群里
Unless you plan on going back to your herd.
什么，丢下我哥儿们？ 好哥儿们第一
What? And break up the team? Bros before does.
对，好哥儿们第一
Yeah. Bros before does.
嗨，爱鹿特
Hello, Elliot.
你变第二了啦
Catch you later, Boog.
不准锯我的树，你这个哈伯二齿
Hey! Get off my trees, you bucktoothed sporran!
回家的感觉真好
Feels like home, baby.
布谷
Hey, Boog!
-兔子大战 -你肖想哦
- Rabbit fight! - Oh, no, you didn't.
是吗，吃我的兔子
Oh, yeah? Well, eat rabbit.
嘿，哥儿们
Hey, buddy.
巴伯…
Bob! Bob!
活生生的野生大人猿标本
A real live homo-sasquatchus.
等等…不…
Wait, wait. No. No. No!